There's one more report I would like to explore in a bit more detail.
هنالك تقرير آخر أريد استطلاعه بالمزيد من التفصيل.
But first, let me tell you a story.
لكن أولاً، دعوني أخبركم بقصة.
A while back I was consulting for a large and successful lifestyle website.
قبل فترة، كنت مستشارة لموقع عن نمط حياة كبير وناجح.
They were ready to redesign their website and they wanted some help.
كانوا مستعدين لإعادة تصميم موقعهم، وأرادوا بعض المساعدة.
I sat down with one of their main salespeople.
جلست مع أحد مندوبي مبيعاتهم الرئيسيين.
He told me they had made a few decisions already.
أخبرني أنهم سبق واتخذوا بعض القرارات.
There was an area of the website with lots of pictures sent in
كان هنالك مكان في الموقع يحوي الكثير من الصور التي تم إرسالها
by users of the site where they showcased their remodel.
من قبل مستخدمي الموقع، حيث قاموا بعرض تجديداتهم.
Now the sales guy did not like this part of the site at all
لم يُعجب مندوب المبيعات بهذا الجزء من الموقع على الإطلاق،
because it was incredibly hard to sell advertising for this section.
لأنه كان من الصعب جداً بيع الإعلانات لهذا القسم.
None of the big appliance brands that he talked to,
لم ترد أي العلامات التجارية الكبيرة التي تكلم معها
wanted to have their ads appear next to someone's new but not so great looking kitchen.
ظهور إعلاناتها بجانب مطبخ جديد وليس برائع لشخص ما.
So they decided this area had to go.
لذا قرروا إلغاء هذه المنطقة.
Now when we dug into Google Analytics,
عند تعمقنا في Google Analyitics
it became clear that this pre-post remodeling content was very popular with users.
أصبح من الواضح أن محتوى إعادة التصميم ما قبل النشر كان رائجاً مع المستخدمين.
They were some of the most visited pages and these pages were engaging,
كانوا من أكثر الصفحات الزيارة، وكانت هذه الصفحات جذابة،
low bounce rates, long time spent, et cetera.
بمعدل خروج متدني، وجلسات المستخدمين كانت طويلة، إلخ...
But what was more,
لكن ما كان أكثر من ذلك،
when we looked at the page flow,
هو عند نظرنا إلى تدفق الصفحة،
we noticed that in many cases
لاحظنا أنه في العديد من الحالات
the second interaction was with content in the designer section,
كان التفاعل الثاني مع المحتوى في قسم المصمم،
where designers were showcasing their remodels.
حيث كان المصممون يعرضون إعادات تصاميمهم.
Of course this area was way more slick and very popular among advertisers.
بالطبع كانت هذه المنطقة أكثر جاذبية ورواجاً بين المعلنين.
So I sat down again with a salesperson and I told
لذا اجتمعت مجدداً من مندوب المبيعات وقلت له
him I thought the user-generated content should stay.
أنني أعتقد أنه على المحتوى الموّلد من المستخدمين البقاء.
These were pages that inspired users to check out some of the designer's pages.
كانت تلك صفحات هي التي ألهمت المستخدمين لتفقد بعض صفحات المصممين.
And instead of making them disappear,
وبدلاً من جعلها تختفي،
we should promote them, make them more prominent and easy to find.
علينا الترويج لها وجعلها أكثر بروزاً وسهولة للإيجاد.
But I also told him that he should not be worried about pushing them in a sales call.
لكني قلت له أيضاً أنه لا يجب أن يقلق حول الترويج لها خلال نداء المبيعات.
He should use them as a traffic driver to
عليه استخدامها كموجه حركة
the areas that mattered more to him and to his clients,
إلى المناطق الأكثر أهمية له ولعملائه.
the designer showcase pages.
وهي صفحات عرض المصممين.
And so the user-generated content pages were saved and they drove
بذلك قد تم حفظ صفحات توليد المحتوى من قبل المستخدمين، وتسببوا
an increasing amount of traffic to the areas that paid off for the company.
بزيادة الحركة إلى الأماكن المربحة للشركة.
So which report in Google Analytics helped me to figure this out?
إذن أي تقرير في Google Analytics قد ساعدني في معرفة هذا؟
The behavior flow report,
كان تقرير تدفق السلوك،
in the behavior reports section helps to get
يساعد قسم تقارير السلوك بالحصول
a view on how people flow from one page to the
على فكرة عن كيفية تدفق الناس من صفحة
next and what the role is of a page in flowing
إلى أخرى، وما هو دور الصفحة في تدفق
traffic to other important pages. Let's take a look.
الحركة إلى صفحات مهمة أخرى. لنلقي نظرة.